1389 NE Alex Way, Apt# 224 Hillsboro, OR – 97124

TEJDEEP KAUTHARAM

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tejdeepkautharam

SUMMARY

Computer Engineering (Computer Systems) graduate student with two years of professional experience and three months of internship experience in software development looking for full time opportunity. Core Competencies include:

Proficient in C++ and Java

Good OOP design

• Sound knowledge of algorithms and data structures

• Familiar with agile methodologies and SDLC

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Engineering (Computer Systems)

Aug 2014 - May 2016

Email: tkauthar@asu.edu

Mobile: (612)-669-6905

Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ.

ug 2014 – May 201

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication

CGPA: 3.7

CGPA: 3.87

Pondicherry University, Pondicherry, India

Aug 2008 - May 2012

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages C, C++, C#, SQL, Java, Python.

Web Technologies HTML5, CSS3, ASP.NET MVC5, ADO.NET, XML, OWL, PHP, AJAX, JavaScript, JQuery, AngularJS.

Operating Systems LINUX, Windows XP/7/8.

Tools Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Protégé, Eclipse, Matlab, Visual Studio, GIT, MS Office.

Databases HDFS, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server 2008/10.

GRADUATE COURSEWORK

Big Data Computing, Information Retrieval Mining and Integration, Distributed Database Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Distributed multi-processor OS, Distributed Software Development, Data Mining, Computer Systems (Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Computer Networks), communication networks.

GRADUATE PROJECTS

Spatial Spark - Geospatial Operations on Distributed Data

Aug 2015 - Dec 2015

- Designed and developed an application to implement Geo Spatial operations like Closest and Farthest Pair, Convex Hull, Geometric Union and Spatial Join using OOP concepts in Java on a distributed processing framework Apache Spark.
- Implemented Range partition, Round Robin partition, Parallel Join and Parallel Sort in Python using multi-threading concepts on the data stored in PostgreSQL.

Optical Character Recognition (OCR)

Nov 2015 - Dec 2015

• Extracted text from image sources by designing and implementing Multi Class Perceptron Classifier and MIRA classifier using Python. Trained and tested these classifiers on set of scanned handwritten digit images.

Search Engine Implementation

Jan 2015 - Apr 2015

- Developed the Vector Space Model using just TF/IDF weights to rank the documents in JAVA using LUCENE indexer.
- Developed the Authorities/Hub and Page Rank computation in JAVA on 25054 pages corpus and displayed matched results.
- Developed the clustering of results using K-means algorithm obtained on the top N results using TF/IDF.

Hotel Booking System

Feb 2015 - Apr 2015

- Developed a Hotel booking system in C# by using multi-threading concepts that handles multiple booking transactions.
- Developed SOAP and RESTful location based services in C# and developed a 3-tier ASP. Net website which offers these services.

Message Passing in Client Server Application

Sep 2014 - Dec 2014

- Developed non-preemptive scheduler in C on Linux by developing queues and Thread Controlled Blocks (TCB).
- Developed semaphore's routines in C and used them to achieve synchronization among multiple threads.
- Developed network API's to send and receive data from local/remote ports in a distributed OS environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer, Intel Corporation, Hillsboro, OR, USA.

Statistical Process Control (SPC)

Jun 2016 -Present

• Developing Process Control Review System in C# for Statistical Process Control ASP.NET MVC5 web application.

Software Developer Intern, Intel Corporation, Santa Clara, CA, USA.

Camera Module Simulator (CMS)

May 2015 -Dec 2015

- Developed command line utility in C++ for CMS that generates configuration files based on the command line parameters.
- Developed website for CMS and automated CMS input parameter generation using PHP and JavaScript.

Assistant System Engineer, Tata Consultancy Services Pvt. Ltd., Chennai, India.

Nielsen Answers Portal (https://nielseninreview.nielsen.com)

Aug 2012 -Jun 2014

• Designed and developed core business modules in C# and developed converters that converts raw sales data given by retail stores into suitable file formats and loads them into relational database using SQL Bulk loading utilities.